B2B Cambodia, the portal for business
use in Cambodia.
The American University of Ponumping and
Manual Life Cambodia signs the
immemorandum of understanding on May 12,
2025, marking a shared commitment to
equipping Cambodia's next generation of
leaders with needed knowledge,
experience, and vision to thrive in a
rapidly changing economy. Under this new
partnership, students at AUP will be
given a chance to gain real world
industry experience through manual life
programs while staff of the insurance
company will have the opportunity to
access AUP academic programs, expertise
and professional development resources
at a special discounted rate.
I believe that through this
collaboration we aspire to make a
lasting impact for on Cambodia and our
people by combining the AUP academic
excellence with many life innovative
insurance solution. We are not only
investing in the individual future but
also contributing to the nation's
journey toward becoming an upper middle
income economy by 2030s and a high
income economy by 2050. It is a
collaboration rooted in a common purpose
to equip Cambodia's next generation of
leaders with the knowledge, experience,
and vision that they will need to thrive
in a rapidly changing
economy. As one of Cambodia's leading
universities, AUP has always believed in
the power of real world engagement.
We spoke with Dr. Marco Mcclever,
president of AUP and Rotach Chan, CEO
and general managers of manual life
Cambodia to learn more about this
partnership. Today is an opportunity for
a to demonstrate what we refer to as a
realworld education. We passionately
believe that education has to be
relevant to the real world. And one of
the ways in which we achieve this is
partnering with the leading companies in
Cambodia to give our students the
opportunity to experience real world ex
situations. But it goes beyond that.
It's also an opportunity for AUP to try
and make a difference and to add value
to the local community. We passionately
believe that an educational institution
isn't just about giving out
certificates. It's about adding the
value to the lives of all Cambodians.
Manual Life has a very impressive record
when it comes to corporate social
responsibility. They share the same
values as us. So this is an opportunity
for our students not only to engage with
industry but also to engage with some of
the wonderful projects that Manual Life
are doing in the community. AUP has been
known for the commitment to provide
quality high worldclass educations and
for me education is the backbone for the
country economy for the country pro
prosperities and the country effort to
move the country to uh a development
stage that we want to achieve by 2030s
and by 2050. And uh looking at manual
life, we have the same missions to build
a better and healthier financial future
for Cambodian family. And for me
personally, education is so important is
the bridge together there. So by working
together manualize and AUP it has allow
to magnifies our effort to reach the
common goals and common missions
building a better and healthier
financial future for Cambodian families
through this quality educations. And to
start with we will offer a lot of
benefit you know discounts uh to the
customer of both uh uh institutions
manual life and AUP. At the same time we
will uh promote the engagement activity
working with the students of AUPP
allowing the internship opportunities,
mentorship opportunities maybe and also
career counseling opportunity and and
also for me personally I want to bring
about the innovation uh into the lion
children and we need new mind bright
idea from young bright minds people just
like the students of AUP students will
certainly be given the opportunity for
internship ships. They'll be able to
work alongside the staff at Manu Life.
They'll be able to experience real world
industry situations. They will also be
given the opportunity to work on some of
the the CSR project such as the
Ankorwatt International half marathon
and they'll be able to work on maybe the
marketing activities and some of the
event organizations in relation to that.
In addition to that, the staff at Manion
Life will also be able to spend time at
the university. we'll be able to help
and support them in terms of their
professional development and again as I
said we'll be able to work on the CSR
projects together. So it affords both
our staff, manual life staff and our
students a wide range of activities
[Music]